A Guide to the Leon M. Bazile Hanover County Records, 1796-1842
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Leon M. Bazile Hanover County Records, 1796-1842
The Library of Virginia
22467
20 leaves, negative photostats
Leon M. Bazile
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying 17 August 1945, by Leon M. Bazile, Elmont, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Leon Maurice Bazile was born 9 September 1890 in Hanover County, Virginia to Aime Maurice Bazile (1848-1928) and Josephine Fox Bazile (1858-1926). He attended Hanover County public and private schools and Richmond College, from where he earned his LLB in 1910. Bazile practice law in Richmond, Virginia, until 1916, when he became assistant attorney-general for Virginia. Retiring from that post in 1930, he returned to private practice. In 1935, he was elected to represent Hanover and King William Counties in the Virginia House of Delegates. He served in the House until appointed judge of 15th judicial circuit court from 1941 until his retirement in 1965. Bazile was also a historian of Hanover County and active in education. He married Virginia Hamilton Bowcock (1889-1970) of Alabama 26 January 1918, and they had one daughter. Bazile died 18 March 1967 at his home "Retirement" in Hanover County and was buried in the family plot.
Scope and Content
Hanover County, Virginia, records, 1796-1842, collected by Leon M. Bazile (1890-1967) of Hanover County consisting of deeds, 1796-1829, and surveys, 1796, for real property in Hanover County, including the Offley Mill tract; plats, no date, of the Offley Mill tract; memoranda, 1837-1842, concerning assignment of a bond and a deed of trust from John Cooke (1801-1861) to Dr. Carter Berkeley; and a copy of the will, 1842, of Samuel Terrell of Caroline County, Virginia. The will is incomplete.
Contents List
- Deed, dated 25 February 1796, recorded 20 July 1796, and acknowledged 18 October 1797, for 50 acres in Hanover County from Philip (1766-1851) and Sarah Burwell (Sally) Nelson (1769-1856) of Frederick County, Virginia, to Clarke Moorman and Robert Honeyman (d. 1824) of Hanover County.
- Survey, November 1796, of 1015 acres in Hanover County belonging to William Fontaine (1754-1810) made by John M. Herndon.
- Survey, November 1796, of 322 acres in Hanover County belonging to Fontaine made by Herndon.
- Deed, dated 3 April 1813 and recorded 25 August 1813, for 244 1/2 acres in Hanover County from Clarke and Rachel Moorman to Robert (1768-1845) and Samuel Terrell (1770-1844) of Caroline County, Virginia.
- Deed, dated 3 April 1813 and recorded 25 August 1813, for 50 acres in Hanover County from Clarke and Rachel Moorman and Charles Thompson (1789-1855) to Robert and Samuel Terrell.
- Deed, dated 6 November 1829 and recorded 25 November 1829, for 277 acres in Hanover County from Dr. Carter Burwell Berkeley (1768-1839), commissioner, to Elizabeth Edmonia Berkeley (1802-1888), both of Hanover County
- Memoranda, 1837, 1840, and 1842, concerning the assignment of a bond and deed of trust from John Cooke (1801-1861) of Hanover County to Dr. Carter Berkeley.
- Copy of the will, 1842, of Samuel Terrell of Caroline County.
- Plat, no date, of the "Offley Mill tract."
- Plat, no date, of the "Offley Mill tract."